Ethan Knight

m: (650) 804-8978 | ethknig@nuevaschool.org

PROJECTS (see also: github.com/hyperdo)

NLP Research — Researching in the field of natural language processing, focusing on machine comprehension and combinatory categorical grammar

Machine Learning - ADHD classification project for a medical device

Nueva Programming Puzzles and Code Golf – Co-founder and author of the site that administers competitive programming challenges <u>ppcgnueva.tk</u>.

The Luca Bazooka – A Raspberry Pi+Arduino programmed robot to recognize and detect my classmate Luca's face as a target. Used OpenCV, SciPy stack.

Cyber-Political Research Project – Year-long research project relating to connected computing, global relations, and policy. **Quest.ethanknight.xyz**

USA Computing Olympiad (USACO) — Competing at Gold level.

Google FooBar Level 4 at age 14; too young to advance in the interview process.

RELEVANT COURSEWORK AND SKILLS

9th grade: Calculus, Cryptology, Computer Science, Mechatronics 10th grade: Multivariable Calculus, Linear Algebra, Machine Learning, Applied Mathematics

Languages: *Proficient*: Python (5-6 y.), LaTeX (3 y.). *Experience with*: C++ (1-2 y.), Mathematica (1 y.), Julia (1 y.)

 $\textbf{\textit{Libraries:}}\ \textit{Proficient:}\ \textit{SciPy stack (NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, SKLearn,}$

etc.), Flask, Asymptote, spaCy, Keras.

Experience with: NLTK, OpenCV, TFLearn/TensorFlow

ACADEMIC AWARDS

The Copernicus Prize, 2016 – 1st Place Award of \$10,000 for essay & video **Caroline D. Bradley Scholarship** – Merit scholarship for 4 years of HS tuition

EMPLOYMENT

League Fellow Paid internship with League of Creative Minds – Summer 2016 **Ethan's Hub** On–Demand 3D Printing Service – April 2016 to present **Fencing Referee** for local & national foil events – 2014 to present

ACTIVITIES

Nationally-Ranked Foil Fencer; League of Creative Minds, Model U.N. team (commendations: Harvard, MIT, Stanford, Georgetown NAIMUN); French Club, Community Service Club, Programming Contest Club (co-founder)

1171 Fife Avenue Palo Alto, California 94301

EDUCATION

The Nueva School — August 2015 to June 2019

Crystal Springs Uplands School — 2012 to 2015

TEST SCORES

ACT — Sept. 2016 (10th grade)
Composite: 35 (PR: 99.7)

* English: 36 (PR: 99.96)

* Mathematics: 35 (PR: 99.7)

* Reading: 34 (PR: 99.1)

* Science: 36 (PR: 99.96)

ACT STEM Index: 36

PSAT — *Oct.* 2016, 10th grade * Composite: 1520/1520

SAT 2 Subject Tests* Math 2: 800 (9th grade)

SUMMER PROGRAMS

2016 LCM League Fellow

2015 ProveIt! Math Camp

2014 Quantum Camp Chemistry & International Fencing Camp, Poland

2013 AwesomeMath & League of Creative Minds

2012 Stanford MS Summer Institute, Physical Science & Epsilon Math, 2nd Yr Prog.

PRIOR ACADEMIC AWARDS

- * Award of High Distinction, League of Creative Minds, 2014
- * AMC-8 Honor Roll 2014
- * Duke Univ. Talent Search
- Grand Ceremony, 2014
- * Julian C. Stanley Study of Exceptional Talent (SET)
- * Davidson Young Scholars